ACTWU's Vice-President's Office Records 5619/029
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACTWU's Vice-President's Office Records
1960-1979
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union
Sol Brandzel
Charles English
Howard Samuel
5619/029
11.33 cubic feet
11.3 linear feet
Correspondence, reports, publications.
This collection consists of correspondence, reports, and files from the Vice-President's Offices for Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America and Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union. During the time period of these records, this office was held by Sol Brandzel, Charles English, and Howard Samuel.
6826508
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
July 2010
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 2011
Biographical / Historical
The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an arbitration system to settle disputes.
Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not change for many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having precedence over those of locals.
Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants.
Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management.
Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D. Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union, which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable.
During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the union's political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union's existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a troubled union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related collections: 5619: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America 5619/004: ACTWU's Jacob Sheinkman Records from the Sectretary-Treasurer's and President's Offices 5619/004 mf: ACTWU's Microfiche Collection of Jacob Sheinkman's Speeches 5619/006: ACTWU's Executive Vice-President's Office Records 5619/018: ACTWU's Secretary-Treasurer's Office Records 5619/030: ACTWU's General Executive Board (GEB) Records 5619/036: ACTWU's Murray Finley Records from the President's Office 5619/036 mf: ACTWU's Microfilm of Murray Finley's Correspondence from the President's Office And all other 5619 collections.
Textile industry--New York (State)--New York; Textile workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York; Clothing trade--New York (State)--New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Archives; Brandzel, Sol, 1913-2003; English, Charles; Samuel, Howard, 1924-2003
6826508
- Referendum Vote, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Resolutions: No Folders Typed, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary).
- A-1: Report to the Officers, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A-2: Organizing, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- A-3: Union Label, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- A-4: Amalgamated Health and Welfare Programs, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- A-5: Amalgamated Banks, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- A-6: Amalgamated Education Program, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- A-7: Amalgamated Pension and Retiree Services, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- A-8: Amalgamated Co-Operative Housing, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- A-9: Industrial Matters, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- A: Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- B-1: Economic Policy, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary). Includes the War on Poverty
- B-2: Wage and Hour Legislation., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary). Includes Walsh Healy
- B-3: Unemployment Compensation, Workmen's Compensation, and Social Security, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- B-4: Medicare, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary). Includes AMA (American Medical Association)
- B-5: Political Education, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary). Includes Reapportionment
- B-6: Urban Affairs and Housing, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- B-7: Immigration, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- B-8: Federal Aid to Education, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- B-9: Regional Development and Conservation, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- B-10: Women's Rights, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- B-11: Labor Legislation, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- B-12: Civil Rights, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary). Includes Voting Rights.
- B-13: Civil Liberties, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary). Includes House Un-American Activities Committee.
- B-14: The Radical Right, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- B-15 Depressed Areas and Manpower Retraining, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- B-16: Congressional Reform, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- B-17: Consumer's Rights, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- B: Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- C-1: Foreign Policy, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Resolutions for the 24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary). Includes the Search for Peace.
- C-2: Boys' and Girls' Towns of Italy, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- C-3: Israel, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- C-4: ORT, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- C-5: United Italian American Labor Council, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- C-6: Imports, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- C-7: Canada, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- C: Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Law and Constitution, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Resolutions Referred to GEB, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Convention Key Chains, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  24th Biennial Convention (Fiftieth Anniversary).
- AI: Industrial Matters, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Resolutions for the 25th Biennial Convention
- AM: Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- B: Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Resolutions for the 25th Biennial Convention. Includes Jury Duty.
- Law and Constitution, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Amalgamated Pension Program, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Amalgamated Insurance Program, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Convention Transcript. Partial., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  25th Biennial Convention
- Arkansas Southwest Regional Joint Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Baltimore Joint Board [folder 1 of 3], 1971 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Baltimore Joint Board [folder 2 of 3], 1971 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Baltimore Joint Board [folder 3 of 3], 1971 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Boston Joint Board, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Buffalo Joint Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Capital District Joint Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Central States Joint Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Chicago Joint Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Detroit and Midwestern States Joint Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Eastern Pennsylvania Clothing Workers Joint Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- El Paso, Texas, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Empire Shirt Trimming, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Atlanta, GA
- Enterprise Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Etowah Industries, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Etowah, TN
- Evergreen Textile, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Ferster, Bernard, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Finance Department, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Financial Reports, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Flavell, Tom, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Flickstein, Attorney, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Forest Hills Sportswear, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Formerly Ironall
- Foster, L. W., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- G. G. Manufacturing, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Halls, TN
- Gant Corporation of Connecticut, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Garan, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  See also: Myra Mills
- Gary Company, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Gallatin, TN
- GEB (General Executive Board), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Georgia Joint Board, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Georgia Joint Board, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Government Contracts, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Glove Cities Area Joint Board, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Greenfield Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Greensfelder, Hemker, Weisse, Gale, and Chappelow, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Guin Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Hiland Limited, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Miami, FL
- Hillman Foundation, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- IUD (Industrial Union Department), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Insurance Department, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Insurance Program Booklets, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Cotton Garment Allied Industries
- Inter-Office Memos, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Ironall Fashions, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Lawrenceburg, TN
- IUD Campaign, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- J & H Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Centerville, TN
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Adamsville, TN
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Albany, NY
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  General
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Middlesboro, KY
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Troy, NY
- F. Jacobson and Sons, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Jay Garment, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Jay Garment, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Notes and Letters
- Jay-Mar Ruby, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Charleston, SC
- Jimmy-Richards, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  Hawkinsville, GA
- Kentuckiana Joint Board, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Knickerbocker Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  West Point Miss
- Knox Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Knoxville Glove Workers, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Knoxville, TN
- Kullman, Frederick A., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  Attorney for Myra Mills
- David Kurtz Company, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Labor Market Letter, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Lake Butler Apparel, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Laundry Workers Joint Board, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Laundry Workers Joint Board, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Donald S. Lavigne, Inc., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Learners Requested-Protested, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Lee County Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  Leesburg, GA
- Legal Department, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Lehigh Valley Joint Board, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Lewisburg Sportswear Company, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Rob Roy. Lewisburg, TN
- Lodge, Erwin, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Attorney. Lodge and Goldman
- Louisville Garment, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Louisville, KY
- Lou's Tailoring and Uniform Company, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- McEwen Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  McEwen, TN
- McGregor-Donigan, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Weaver, Windon, and Waldon
- Mid-South Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Richton, MS
- Midwest Regional Joint Board, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Chicago, IL
- Macon Garment, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Macon, MS
- Mal Marshall, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Arbitration
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Ashburn, GA
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Jessup, GA
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Kingston, NY
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Lexington, NC
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Negotiation Folder
- Manhattan Shirt, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Warehouse. Winnsboro, SC
- Martin Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Ramer, TN
- Martin Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Martin Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Martin Manufacturing, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Awards. 3rd and 4th Quarters
- Memo For Files, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Midland Shirt Company, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Midwest Regional Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Minnesota Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Mississippi Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Montreal Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Neckwear Workers Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- New England Regional Office, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- New Haven, CT. Local 125, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- New Orleans Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- New York Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- New York. Local 4, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- New York. Local 169, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- New York. Local 324, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- New York. Local 340, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Northern Alabama Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Northern California Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Cincinnati Joint Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Cleaners and Dyers Joint Board, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Cleveland Joint Board, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Frontlash. Appeals and Contributions, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Frontlash. Training Institute, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  Gettysburg, PA
- DuChessi, William. Appointments, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- DuChessi, William. Memos from his Secretary, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- DuChessi, William. Payroll Memos [folder 1 of 2], 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- DuChessi, William. Payroll Memos [folder 2 of 2], 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Notes From the Joint Economic Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  v.4:no.7 (1978:Mar. 17) - v.5:no.14 (1979:June 26). Incomplete.
- Justice on the Job, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- K. Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- L. Miscellaneous, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Labor Law Reform, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- J. Miscellaneous, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Japan Conference, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Labor Reports, 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- League for Industrial Democracy, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Levi Strauss, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Legal Department. Henry Woicik, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Resource Center for Consumers of Legal Services, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Legal Bills, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Irving Abramson File, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- M. Miscellaneous, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- TWUA-ACWA Merger, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Magazine Subscription File, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Managerial Rebates, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Manpower Education Institute, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Manpower Staff, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Maurer, Fleisher, Zon, and Anderson, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Midwest Handbag Company, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  St. Louis, MO
- Minimum Wage Bill, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Montgomery Mills, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Morgan, Lewis, and Bockius, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Counselors at Law
- Mortuary Fund Report, 1968-1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous File, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- NCARL (National Committee Against Repressive Legislation, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- National Council of Senior Citizens, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- AFL-CIO, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- COPE Memos, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Leo Arnoult's Reports, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Minnesota Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Mid-Atlantic Region. Pam Woywod, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Regional Coordinator's Reports
- Western Pennsylvania and Ohio Region. Bill Patterson, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Northwest Region. Ruth Miller, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Southern California Region. Miriam Ludwig, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Middle West Region. Tom Herriman, Bronwen Zwimer, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Southwest Region. Mary Elkuss, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Southern Region. Rose Bush, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Southern Region. Rose Bush, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- New England Region. Charles Atkinson, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous File, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Staff Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Includes Congressional District Committee Regional Conferences
- Congressional District Committee Meeting, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Washington, DC
- Marginal District Activity, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Congressional District Committee
- Look at the Voting Record, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- House Judiciary Committee, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Pix for Action [folder 1 of 2], 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Pix for Action [folder 2 of 2], 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Back File [folder 1 of 3], 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  CDC Reports, Photographs, etc.
- Back File [folder 2 of 3], 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Back File [folder 3 of 3], 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Cleaners and Dyers, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Common Cause [folder 1 of 2], 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Common Cause [folder 2 of 2], 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- AFL-CIO, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union), 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- APEC (Amalgamated Political Education Committee), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Advance, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Federal Miscellaneous Issues, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Elections, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Elections. Carey Campaign, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Dumping, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Cope, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Convention, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Illegals, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- IUD (Industrial Union Department), 1966-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- U.S. Catholic Conference, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Membership Lists, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Board of Directors, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Mailings and Meetings
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Board of Directors, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Meeting. December 15, 1975
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Board of Directors, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Meeting. October 23, 1975
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Board of Directors, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Meeting. April 11, 1975
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Board of Directors, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Step By Step Program on Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- National Committee for Full Employment. Full Employment Action Council. Activities for Full Employment Bill of 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Joint Council on Economic Education, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Mexico, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Minimum Wage [folder 1 of 2], 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Minimum Wage [folder 2 of 2], 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous Issues, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- New York City Council on Economic Education, 1969-1974 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1966-1973 (Box 6, Folder 22)